♪〜
〜♪
（女性たちの笑い声）
How long are you going to
keep me cooped up in this place?
（Ｅ･Ｇ･マイン）
いつまでこんな所に
閉じ込めておくつもりだ
うだうだやってるあいだに
２人のバカがやられちまったよ
He got two of your idiots
while we twiddled our thumbs.
You should have
let me handle it.
俺に任せねえから
こういうことになるんだよ
Then I'll let you go next.
（レガート･ブルーサマーズ）
なら次は君に任せるよ
舞台は僕が整える
I will set the stage.
Entertain him with what you do best.
君なりの演出で
彼をもてなしてくれ
（マイン）
ヘヘヘヘ… 話せるねえ
You can be reasoned with. I hope
you're as reasonable with my reward.
その調子で報酬も頼むぜ
Are you going to
make him go alone, sir?
（ミッドバレイ）やつ一人に
やらせるおつもりですか？
Hardly.
フッ まさか
The audience gets more pleasure
from a drama with a twist.
意外性があるドラマのほうが
観客は喜んで見てくれる
The more tragic the tragedy,
the greater the emotional effect.
それが悲劇であればあるほど
より心に響くはずだよ
フフッ
（グラスをはじく音）
It's been two whole weeks now...
（ミリィ･トンプソン）
もう２週間 たっちゃいましたね
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
ここまでだ 一緒に旅をするのは
This is as far as
we can travel together.
（メリル･ストライフ）
どうして？
Why?
Yourjob or your life...
命と仕事
どっちが大切なんだい？
... which is more important?
理由は言わない
I won't say why.
言ったら巻き込まれるから
If I did, you would
be drawn into it.
なかなか楽しかったよ
Well, it's been fun!
But this is it.
でも ここまでだ
I wonder how Mr. Vash is doing?
（ミリィ）ヴァッシュさん
どうしてるでしょうね？
あの人のことですから—
You know him! He's undoubtedly
goofing around in some town!
どこかの町で
のうのうと暮らしてますわよ
ああ…
Hey, did you hear?
（男性Ａ）おい 聞いたかよ
（メリルとミリィ）あっ？
Remember the guy in the white coat
who caused the saloon riot?
（男性Ａ）
この前 酒場で暴れまくった
白いコートの男
あいつも
ヴァッシュの手下だったらしいぜ
It looks like he's
one of Vash's men.
Aha! That explains why
his methods were so vicious!
（男性Ｂ）なるほど
あの えげつないやり方も
それなら うなずけるってもんだ
But he took off.
（男性Ｃ）だが やつは去った
Yeah! We should count our blessings
that we got off so easy!
（男性Ｂ）ああ あの程度の
被害だけで済んだんだから—
幸運だと思わないとな
（男性Ｃ）
赤いコートを着た悪魔か
He's a devil in a red coat.
Damn. I wish
he'd drop dead!
（男性Ａ）クソッ
とっとと くたばれってんだ！
How can you say
that about him?!
どうして
そんなこと言うんですの？
（男性たち）うん？
You don't even know
what kind of a person he is!
あなた方は あの人がどういう人か
分かってないくせに
（３人）ああ？
Ma'am?
先輩…
えっ？
アハ アハ アハハハ…
Walk your own path
with your head held high...
“自分の道をしっかりと
胸を張って歩きなさい” …か
- Milly?
- Yes, ma'am?
（メリル）ミリィ
（ミリィ）はい
Stop wasting time here,
we have work to do!
こんな所で油売ってないで
仕事続けますわよ
（ミリィ）はい
Yes, ma'am!
We will follow him
to the ends of the earth!
地の果てまでも
あの人を追いかける
For that is
what we must do!
それが 私たちの
やるべきことなのですから
（電波親父(おやじ)の鼻歌）
Hello, chair!
How ya been?
（電波親父）やあ いす君
元気なのかい？
（鼻歌）
うわーっ
Legato...
（ヴァッシュ）レガート
今度は お前を追いかける番だ
...this time it's
my turn to hunt you.
見つけ出す なんとしても…
I will find you,
whatever it takes.
Yeah, right!
（ヴァッシュ）なーんてな
（電波親父）ああ？
カッチョよく考えてみたけど—
It sounded real cool
in my head...
...but I haven't got a clue
how I'm going to find him.
どうやったら
やつの足取りがつかめるのか—
全然 分かんないじゃん
トホホホホ…
Not only that, the more I think about it,
the more frightening it becomes...
しかも よくよく考えたら—
だんだん恐ろしさに
足がガクガクしてきちゃったよ
...and now my legs are
starting to knock together!
相手は あの男なんだー！
Good God, I have to fight HI M!!!
Will I survive a fight with a guy who
makes those evil eyes when he smiles?!
あんな目をして笑うやつに
ケンカふっかけて—
俺は大丈夫か？
No, I'm gonna be slaughtered,
that's what! It's not funny!!
いやー 全然 大丈夫じゃない
まったくもって しゃれにならん！
I should back away from it.
That's what I should do.
やめとくか
そんな感じがいいな
Yeah, yeah! For once,
that is an excellent idea.
うんうん
我ながら いい考えだ
You're the one who isn't funny!
What are ya, a radio?!
（電波親父）
しゃれにならんのは お前だ！
電波か？ 電波なのか？ お前は
やっぱ 人生
楽しく生きなくちゃね
Life is meant to be fun, right?
ああ… モグモグモグ
That's super-tasty!
あー 激うま！
Hey, mister! I'll have
another salmon sandwich!
マスター サーモンサンド追加ね
うん？
うわっ
オッ オー ガスタ…
A... Augusta...
I'll be waiting
for you in Augusta City.
オーガスタシティーで待ってる…
You will acknowledge
my request.
申し出を受けてもらうよ
If you do not,
this is what will happen.
そうじゃないと こうなるから…
やめろ！
Stop!!
（銃声）
（客たち）うおおっ！
Who did this?!
だ… 誰が
あっ 血が出てない
There's no blood!
あっ おっ 何？
Huh? What? You know him?!
Do you know this guy?
なんじゃ？ あんた 知り合い？
この人 知り合い？
He's the only one capable of this!
（ヴァッシュ）
あんなことができるのは
やつしかいない
What is it? Huh?
Legato!
レガート
You called him? He your friend?
Hey, is he your friend?
（電波親父）呼んだの？ 仲間？
ねえ 仲間？
Do you want me there so badly,
you would kill an innocent?
（ヴァッシュ）
人の命を奪ってまで
俺を呼び出したいのか
All right, I'll go there, Legato.
I'll go to your home ground.
行ってやるよ レガート
お前のホームグラウンドへな
Who are you?
（電波親父）えっ 何者？
（ヴァッシュ）ん？
誰なんだ？ あんた！
Who the heck are you?!
（男性の荒い息）
（バーテン）
どうしたんだ そんなに慌てて…
Hey, where's the fire?
（男性）た… 大変だ！
L-Listen! He's here!!
It's Vash the Stampede!!
現れたんだよ
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードが
Are you sure?
（メリル）ホ… ホントですの？
Yeah! He's running rampant through
Augusta, shooting off his silver gun!
（運転手）ああ
銀色の銃を撃ちまくって—
オーガスタで暴れまくってやがる
That crazy bastard is going to
do to Augusta what he did toJuly!
（男性）
あの野郎 ジュライの次は
オーガスタをやる気らしい
It's a good thing we found him!
見つかってよかったですね
What is he thinking?
（メリル）あの人
いったい何を考えてるんですの？
MY NAME IS...
（ヴァッシュ）俺の名は—
...VASH THE STAMPEDE!!!
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードだ
（ざわめき）
Forgive the lack of warning,
but it's time for my daily massacre!
（ヴァッシュ）突然で悪いが
今から 俺的 皆殺しタイムに入る
If you do not believe
I am the real thing...
俺が本人でないと思うんなら
この姿を見て驚きなさーい！
...take a good look at me
and start freaking!!
赤いコートとラブリーな金髪
Observe my red coat,
lovely blond locks...
...and my 100%
accurate gunmanship!
そして 百発百中のガンさばき
（銃声）
（黒猫の鳴き声）
（人々の悲鳴）
（銃声）
Anyway, if you don't wanna die,
get 100 iles away from this place...
とにかく死にたくなかったら
ここより100アイル離れて—
...and live happily ever after!!
ハッピーに生きよう！
That's the last of them.
（ヴァッシュ）
これで全部終わりっと
Why couldn't that nihilist
have picked a better location?!
しかし なんて場所選ぶんだよ
あのニヒル野郎
I used up all my energy
just chasing people out.
人を追っ払うだけで
体力使いまくって—
もう ヘコヘコ
I'm pooped.
I don't like this.
（ヴァッシュ）イヤな気分だ
あのときのことを思い出しちまう
It reminds me of the other time.
あっ
What?
何だ？
（水滴が落ちる音）
（ヴァッシュ）あっ
血！ あっ
Blood?!
Do you like our
little decorations?
（マイン）お気に召したかね？
負け犬の行く先は
マイホームじゃねえや
Losers don't get to go home.
They go to Hell.
地獄だ！
Did you kill them?
（ヴァッシュ）お前がやったのか？
I am the fifth Gung-Ho Gun.
My name is E. G. Mine!
（マイン）
ガンホーガンズの５(ファイブ)
俺の名は Ｅ･Ｇ･マイン
Did you kill them?!
お前がやったのか？
（マイン）うるさいねえ
Damn, you're noisy...
What if I did, chickenshit?
それが どうだってんだよ
チキン野郎
You don't seem to want to kill anyone,
so someone had to cover your ass!
おめえが
人を殺せねえらしいから—
俺がフォロー
してやってんじゃねえかよ
And besides...
ちなみに お前
もう俺の間合いに入ってるぜ
...you've already fallen into my court.
I've never heard
such a rotten script.
（ヴァッシュ）
どこまで腐ったシナリオだ
So, I have only two choices:
To die or let others die?
俺には 死ぬか死人を出す以外
道が残ってないというのか？
Don't be so huffy!
（マイン）
まあ そうカッカするなって
Only one more has to die.
After I take you down...
死人が出るのは あと１人だよ
俺が今 おめえを倒して
それで終わりと
...it'll all be over!
なにっ？
What?
うっ！
うわーっ
What's the idea?!
な… 何しやがる！
That bastard is trying
to cut in on my action!
野郎
お楽しみを奪いやがって
Had I kept my blade sheathed,
you would have been knocked senseless...
（雷泥(らいでい)･ザ･ブレード）それがしが
今の一太刀を繰り出さねば—
おぬしの意識は絶たれていた
...by your Humanoid Typhoon there.
そこにいるヒューマノイド･
タイフーン殿によってな
（マイン）なんだと！
Say what?!
It looks like you're the favorite.
What's your name?
どうやら
こちらが本命さんのようだな
名前は？
Forgive my lack of manners.
（雷泥）これは失礼つかまつった
それがしは
ガンホーガンズの９(ここのつ)
I am the ninth Gung-Ho Gun...
次元斬一刀流(じげんざんいっとうりゅう) 雷泥･ザ･ブレード
...Rai-Dei the Blade
of theJigenzan-Itto School!
貴殿に恨みはありませぬが
ぜひともシアイを受けてもらいたい
I hold no personal grudge against you,
but I wish to engage you in a Shi-Ai.
シアイ？
A Shi-Ai?
- DEATH MATCH-
I can't read that.
読めましぇーん
If you cannot read Japanese, then I
will explain. Fight me to the death!
ジャパングの文字が分からぬのなら
しかたあるまい
決闘だ！
Are you playing along
with his farce as well?
あんたも
やつの茶番につきあうのか？
I would happily walk the path of
carnage for the mastery of Bushi-Do.
（雷泥）それが 武士道を
極めることになるのなら—
修羅の道に踏み込むのも
また一興
What?
（ヴァッシュ）なにっ？
I refer to what is only visible
from the edge of the deathly abyss.
（雷泥）死のふちに立ってみないと
見えぬ景色もあるということだ
I know you have seen it.
貴殿にも覚えがあろう？
There's nothing to see there.
（ヴァッシュ）何も見えはしないさ
Only fear.
ただ 怖いだけだ
Even so, I also wish to
experience that mental state!
ならば その境地 それがしにも…
ん？
（金属音）
Come on, now...
（マイン）おいおい
こいつを切り刻むのは俺の仕事だよ
It's my job
to dice this guy!
Laughable! It would appear you
didn't hear what I told you earlier.
笑止
先ほどの それがしの話を
聞いていなかったとみえる
You're right, I didn't.
（マイン）ああ 聞いてねえな
（皮が割ける音）
（マイン）ああっ？
Your match was already over.
すでに勝負は決まっていたのだ
His gunmanship! Words fail
to describe its greatness!
（雷泥）なんという単筒(たんづつ)さばき
さすがという以外
言葉が見つからぬわ
That man was never an opponent
to be humbled by you.
そこにおられる方は—
おぬし程度に伏される相手では
なかったのだ
（マイン）ああ…
（雷泥）
座興としては楽しめたと思うが
いかがかな？
Although I think you may
have served to amuse him.
（マイン）ああ…
Why, you...
き… 貴様！
おお… その体から放たれる
あふれんばかりの覇気
The angry aura released
through your every pore!
My knees are quaking
with excitement!
それがしのひざ小僧が
ガクガクと震えていますぞ
This alone makes
my journey worthwhile.
それでこそ来た甲斐(かい)が
あるというもの
This is my
dearest pleasure!
ゆえに これ本懐！
（ヴァッシュ）来な
Come on.
I am in your debt.
かたじけない
Get ready!
いざ！
（銃声）
あっ
いやあーっ！
（銃声）
（金属音）
Give me a real fight!
真剣で お願いしたい
Ever hear of a
warrior's compassion?
（ヴァッシュ）
武士の情けって知ってる？
I can't shoot to kill you.
死んじゃうところには
当てらんないよ
That arrogance is an eyesore! It
blurs the path to spiritual awareness!
（雷泥）
そのおごり 目障りですぞ！
傍観への道がかすむ
People don't change
their ways so easily.
人間 そう性格は変わんないさ
フフッ 人間とは片腹痛い
People? Ridiculous!
（ヴァッシュ）えっ？
（雷泥）それがしも貴殿も
人にあって人にあらず
You and I are men,
yet not of man.
We are dark,
diabolical puppets!
闇に染まりし魔の傀儡(かいらい)
We are demons!!
すなわち 魔人よ！
（崩れ落ちる音）
な… 何ですの？
What is that?!
This isn't a good thing!
とんでもないことになってますね
Do you think it's Vash?
まさか ヴァッシュさん…
Let's move, Milly!
急ぐわよ ミリィ
（ミリィ）あっ 先輩！
- Ma'am!
- What are you doing?!
何ですの？
We can't! It's too
big for us to handle!
ダメです
あんな すごいことに
なってるんですよ
激ヤバです
It's super-dangerous!
I am well aware of the danger!
（メリル）危険は承知のうえですわ
先輩！
Ma'am!!
（銃声）
（金属音）
I told you
I want a real fight!
言ったはずですぞ
真剣を望むと
うおーっ！
（ヴァッシュ）うわあーっ
That's some shock wave!
But it's nothing I can't dodge.
なんて衝撃波だ
だが 避けられないわけじゃない
てーい！
（銃声）
あさっての方向ですぞ
Your bullets
are flying wide!
おっ
You mollycoddle!!
このふぬけが！
（発射音）
（ヴァッシュ）うわあっ！
Compassion, in
the heat of battle?!
この期に及んで情けなど
（銃声）
ああっ！
This is a gross disappointment.
（雷泥）期待外れも甚だしい
（銃声）
（ヴァッシュ）うわーっ
Is this all there is
to Vash the Stampede?
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードは
この程度の男なのか？
これでは何も見えん
It isn't enough.
I don't see anything!
うう…
At least... At the very least,
I want an answer!
（雷泥）
せめて… せめて答えよ
貴殿には今
何が見える？ 何が！
At this moment,
what can you see?
Tell me!
Do you intend to die,
Vash the Stampede?
（レガート）死ぬつもりかい？
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
あ…
It's time to use it.
（レガート）今が使うときだよ
（ヴァッシュ）ああ… うう…
Wh...
使うんだ あれを
Use it.
あれを使うんだ
It's something only you can do.
君にしかできない あれだ
Use it!
使うんだ！
Quickly!!
早く！
No! Stop it!!
イヤだ やめろ！
STOP IT!!!
やめろーっ！
I cannot believe he is
begging for his life!
こやつ 今になって命乞いとは
うっ！ こ… これは
What is this?!
うっ この光は…
This light...
This light!
この光は…
（メリル）こ… これは
Oh, my god...
Mr. Vash meant what he said!
Just look at this place!
（ミリィ）
ヴァッシュさん 本気ですよ
見れば分かります
Where is he?
Where is he?!
どこに… どこにいますの？
あっ
Meryl, where are you going?!
（ミリィ）
ねえ どこ行くんですか？
Let go of me!
Let go of me, Milly!!
放して！ 放しなさい ミリィ
（ミリィ）ああっ
（２人）ああ…
Put me down! Milly!
I want to go there!!
（メリル）降ろして ミリィ
行きたいの！
I have to go there!!
私は行くのよ！
What is this phenomenon?
（雷泥）何なのだ？ この現象は
Is this some sort
of Christian magic?!
バテレンの秘術だとでも
言いたいのか
おっ
うわあーっ！
うう… くっ
うわあっ や… やめろー！
STOP IT!!!
What is this indescribable horror
coursing through my entire body?!
（雷泥）何なのだ…
この全身を駆け巡る
言いようのないおぞましさは
Is this it, the moment
I have been seeking?
これを… このときを
それがしは求めていたのか
Will I finally achieve
spiritual awareness?
この先に傍観があるというのか
No! This thing before me...
否！ ここにあるのは…
RUN!!!
に… 逃げろ！
（雷泥）うわあっ
Run!!!
逃げろ！
What is that?!
What the hell is that?!
何なのだ？
それは いったい何なのだー！
Don't! Stop it!!
ダメだ やめろ やめてくれー！
Please stop it!!!
うわあああっ
What's that?
（ニコラス･Ｄ･ウルフウッド）
何や？
What is that horrific light?!
Did he create that?
この すさまじい光は—
あの男が作り出したもの
なのですか？
That's right. This is his second time
including July 23 years ago.
ああ… 23年前に起きた
ジュライを入れ—
これで２回目だね
フフフフ…
（メリル）
ミリィ お願い！ 放して！
Milly, please!
Let me go!!
I can't do that! If you die,
you'll never see him again!
（ミリィ）ダメです
死んじゃったら もう—
ヴァッシュさんとは
会えないんですよ
あっ
（メリルとミリィの悲鳴）
Ma'am, look!!
（ミリィ）先輩 あれ！
（メリル）えっ？
A hole in the moon...
（メリル）月に 穴が
（雷泥）ハア ハア ハア…
The terror...
なんという恐怖
Only you could survive
something like that.
（ウルフウッド）あないな状況で
生きとるとは さすがやな
Y-You.
（雷泥）お… おぬしは
What happened to
Vash the Stampede?
（ウルフウッド）
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードは
どないなった？
- I don't know.
- Darn.
（雷泥）分からん
（ウルフウッド）さようか
If we act now, we may
be able to defeat that man...
今なら やつを—
あの悪魔のような男を
倒せるやもしれぬ
...that devil of a man.
He is too dangerous to be
left alive. Come, help me to...
あの男を生かしておくのは
危険すぎる
おぬしも一緒に…
I can't do that.
（ウルフウッド）そら アカン
ん… 何を考えておる？ おぬし
Are you insane?!
You and I are...
おぬしと それがしは…
すまんな
Sorry.
（銃声）
Sure, nobody died...
but look at this terrible landscape.
（ウルフウッド）
確かに人は死なんかった
けど この惨状を見てみい
Is this the path
you have chosen?
これが おのれの選んだ道か？
Is it, Vash the Stampede?
そうなんか？
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
Hey, did you hear how The Humanoid
Typhoon showed up in Augusta?
（男性Ａ）聞いたか？ あの
ヒューマノイド･タイフーンが—
オーガスタシティーに現れたって
うわさ
I sure did. They say he managed to
destroy the entire city by himself!
（男性Ｂ）ああ
なんでも たった１人で—
都市を壊滅させたって
話じゃないか
FirstJuly, and now Augusta!
ジュライの次はオーガスタか
What the hell is
that maniac thinking?!
何を考えてやがるんだ
あの悪魔め！
今回の事件で
やつに賭けられてる賞金は—
The bounty on his head
will only get bigger!
さらに増えるだろうよ
（男性Ａ）俺たちが この星で
暮らすことになった原因は—
I'm ready to believe it's his
fault we're stuck on this planet...
すべて やつのせい
...along with all the other
crap I've heard about him.
そんな根も葉もないデマも
今なら本気で信じられそうだぜ
それだけじゃねえ
But there's more. They say he's also
responsible for the hole in the moon!
月に穴をあけたのも やつだってよ
One man could never
pull off a stunt like that!
（男性Ｂ）人間１人の力で—
そんなこと
できるわけねえだろうが！
Chill out! I'm just
telling you what I heard!
（男性Ａ）怒るなって！
俺だって聞いた話なんだからよ
（男性Ｂ）
俺たちゃ 生きているだけでも
感謝すべきなのかもしれねえな
Maybe we should be thankful
we're still alive.
Yeah. You said it.
（男性Ａ）ああ まったくだ
（メリルのすすり泣き）
（ドアが開く音）
先輩 本社からの手紙ですよ
Ma'am, we got a letter
from the main office.
It's finally here...
（メリル）やっと来ましたのね
Their correspondence certainly is slow.
We've been waiting for two weeks!
２週間も待たせるなんて
対応が遅いんですから
"Meryl Stryfe and Milly Thompson...
...are to return to the main office."
“メリル･ストライフと
ミリィ･トンプソンの両名は—”
“本社へ戻られたし”
"Furthermore, in a conference
held the other day, it was decided...
“なお 先日の会議で—”
“ヴァッシュ･
ザ･スタンピードは—”
...that Vash the Stampede be designated
as mankind's first human Act of God."
“人類初の人間災害に
指定されることが決定された”
"Henceforward, no matter
what kind of damage he causes...
“今後 彼の手によって—”
“どのような被害が
起ころうとも—”
...The Bernardelli Insurance Society
will be...
“ベルナルデリ保険協会は—”
“関知…”
...will be...
...uninvolved."
“しない”
こんなこと こんなこと…
This can't be.
This can't be...
...what do they think will change
by making this decision now?
いまさら決定して
何が変わると言うんですの？
先輩…
Ma'am...
（メリルの泣き声）
Mr. Vash, you stupid jerk...
You made her cry!
ヴァッシュさんのバカ！
先輩を泣かすなんて—
I'll never, ever
forgive you for this!
絶対に絶対に 許さないんだから！
（風の音）
♪〜
〜♪
（少年時代のヴァッシュ）
レムは僕に言ったんだ
Rem told me that someone
she loved died on Earth.
地球で 大好きな人が
死んでしまったんだって
She told me she boarded
this ship to start over.
仕切り直すために
この船に乗り込んだんだって
What does it feel like to
have someone you love die?
大好きな人が死んでしまったら
どんな気持ちになるんだろう？
I thought of what it
would be like if Rem died.
僕は レムが
いなくなったときのことを—
考えてみた
When I did, hot water came out
of my eyes. It wouldn't stop.
そしたら 目から熱い水があふれて
止まらなくなった
Rem, I'll be there for you!
I won't leave you alone.
レム 僕がそばにいるよ
僕は 君を一人にしない